Guide to the Charles Ackerman papers, 1861-1882
Ackerman, Charles papers, 1861-1882
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Ackerman papers, 1861-1882.
3966
Charles Ackerman.
.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, military records, and business records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are military records pertaining to Company E of the New York Volunteer Infantry 26th Regiment including a transcription of the document authorizing formation of the New York Volunteers, descriptive lists recording soldiers' information, as well as requests for same, proceedings of courts-martial, discharge notices, receipts, and other items; correspondence between Ackerman and his friends and relatives; and records of Ackerman's general store at Higginsville, Oneida County, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are military records pertaining to Company E of the New York Volunteer Infantry 26th Regiment including a transcription of the document authorizing formation of the New York Volunteers, descriptive lists recording soldiers names, ranks, ages, and details of their enlistment, as well as requests for same, proceedings of courts-martial, discharge notices, receipts, and other items; correspondence between Ackerman and his friends and relatives; and records of Ackerman's general store at Higginsville, Oneida County, New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ackerman, Charles.; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 26th.
Subjects:
General stores--New York (State)--Higginsville.; Stores, Retail--New York (State)--Higginsville.; Soldiers--United States.; Trials (Military offenses)
Places:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Higginsville (N.Y.)--Commerce.; Oneida County (N.Y.)--Commerce.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- "An act to authorize the embodying and equipment of a Voluntary Militia, and to provide for public defense" passed Apr. 16, 1861, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Descriptive Roll of Company E, 26th Regiment New York Volunteer Infantry, 1861-1862 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Military papers, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Military papers, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Military papers, 1864-1865, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters, 1862-1865 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, 1867-1682 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters in German script, 1862-1874 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters in German script, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters in German script, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters in German script, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters in German script, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lottery notice for Braunschweig-Luneburg (in German), 1876 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Envelopes, 1862-1882 (Box 1, Folder 15)